The most important number in private
credit right now is not a dividend yield
or a default rate. It's not some net
asset value or the size of the
marketplace. It's 16.8%.
That is how much of Apollo Debt
Solutions outstanding shares investors
wanted the firm to buy back in the
second quarter. And the reason why it's
such a big deal is because in the first
quarter, they only asked for 11% back,
which means this thing is not
stabilizing. It is still escalating and
it is only the start of this story.
Apollo's president, Jim Zelter, said in
May that he didn't think the withdrawals
were a one-shot. He also said he didn't
expect a dramatic increase in the exit
requests and that there, quote, maybe
even a little bit of an increase. Well,
that prediction has already been
overwhelmed by reality. This was not a
little bit of an increase. Going from
11% to 16.8%
is another major escalation. And it
matters because private credit, as as
we've been saying, is built on
confidence. The industry says
fundamentals are healthy and investors
keep saying, "Then why can't I get more
of my money out?" So, here's the big
question. Why aren't investors buying
the reassurances? And we see this all
over the industry, whether in publicly
traded BDCs like Blue Owl, which keep
hitting new lows, or here in Apollo's
case with a non-traded vehicle.
Investors are fleeing in bigger and
bigger numbers. Think about it this way.
If a money management firm had one out
of six of its clients calling them up
this quarter and wanting to fire them,
the natural reaction wouldn't be that
it's somehow clients overreacting. It
would be to take a hard look at why this
is taking place. And since this is
happening all over the industry, the
explanation has to apply to everyone or
nearly everyone. The assets are likely
rotten or enough of them anyway, and
people know it. Now, what people can't
see is why this matters for anyone who's
not a hedge fund investor who maybe made
some bad decisions. The channel for
contagion is what this is all about.
It's not about Apollo's funds, it's
about what Apollo is doing that you
don't really necessarily know about. So,
we have information on the contagion
channel, what's taking place, why these
redemptions matter, and how they fit
into that process. Because, like I said,
there is a lot going on here that you
don't see. But, let's start with the
basic facts, the latest one. Apollo Debt
Solutions disclosed in the second
quarter of 2026 its gross inflows,
that's money coming in, totaled about
$300 million.
So, some people are still adding new
money. But, during the same period,
investors submitted a repurchase request
equal to approximately 16.8%
of outstanding shares. Like I said, one
in six of Apollo Debt Solutions clients
are saying, "We want to fire you. Want
our money back." And this fund isn't
small, it's about $26 billion, and
Apollo is not honoring all those
redemption requests. It has stated its
quarterly purchase target of 5% of
shares, it's going to stick with that,
no matter what. So, that means Apollo
expects about $700 million of gross
outflows, gross outflows based on the
May 31st net asset value. So, the math
is simple. 300 money coming in, roughly
700 million going out, that means net
outflows of approximately 400 million
for the quarter. So, for the first time,
more money going out than coming in. And
it would be a lot worse if not for that
5% limitation. Now, this isn't an
immediate threat to the fund because it
can handle $400 net, especially as it
has, reportedly, 4.6 billion in
available liquidity, mainly credit lines
with banks that it can draw on if
necessary. Now, Apollo framed this as
consistency. The company said it has a
fiduciary duty to all its investors, and
that adhering to its stated liquidity
targets is important, and that's all
true in a very narrow sense. A fund like
this is not supposed to be a checking
account. These are illiquid loans held
inside a semi-liquid vehicle. If
everyone wants out at once, the manager
has to slow down the process, but that's
exactly the problem. The structure works
beautifully when the money's coming in.
It becomes far more difficult when the
money starts to go out. Stage two. The
biggest change here is that net flows
have now turned negative for the first
time, and that's the moment the money
machine changes direction. A growth
vehicle becomes a liquidity management
vehicle. A lender becomes a seller or at
least a hoarder of cash. A fund that
used to make loans now has to think
about who might ask for their money back
next quarter. It's not just individuals,
I assure you. And it's not a small
change because the implications are
indeed systemic. And of course, managers
all keep saying the same thing. Their
fundamentals are absolutely solid. Why
would anyone want to question either
their performance or their underwriting
standards? And time and again, what we
see is that investors do not buy that
spin. And the question you need to ask
yourself as a start is why not? What
else must be lying inside all of this
shadow bank money?
Before we go on with our video today,
let me ask you a question. What if your
gold could actually pay you every single
month in more gold? That's what today's
video sponsor, Monetary Metals, lets you
do.
And here's how it works. You still own
the gold, it's still in your name, it's
fully insured, but instead of just
sitting there doing nothing, it actually
starts working for you. Monetary Metals
has built a system that turns idle gold
into productive gold, earning real yield
paid in physical gold, not dollars. No
selling, no trading, no converting. You
keep your gold, and every month you get
more of it. It's a simple idea, but it
solves a big problem. If gold is money,
it should act like money, and now it
finally can.
If you're a long-term gold holder
looking for a smarter way to store
value, check them out at
monetary-metals.com/snyder.
Again, that's
I highly recommend booking a call with
them today to see if they're the right
fit for you. We thank Monetary Metals
for their sponsorship, but now let's get
back to the rest of our video.
Now, Apollo's president said the
underlying performance of the funds was,
\quote} solid in March, April, and May.
The industry broadly says borrowers are
still paying, losses are manageable, and
the system is working as it was
designed. But markets are not just what
people say. Markets are what people do,
and investors keep asking for more and
more of their money back. That's the key
contradiction. If everything was so
solid, then why are redemption requests
rising for Apollo from 11% to 16.8%?
One in six. If private credit is so
stable, then why are net flows turning
negative? If investors really believe
the NAV valuations, why are they lining
up to exit at the NAV where it is while
they still can? This is where the
industry spin really starts to break
down because the issue is not whether
every loan is bad. It's course not.
That's not what happens. The issue is
whether enough investors have started to
doubt the marks, doubt the liquidity,
and the ability of these funds to manage
a downturn. Manage a downturn without
trapping them inside. That's the key
here. They know that there's a downturn,
and they can see it coming, and they
don't want to be stuck inside these
funds who will be at the absolute center
of it. Once investors begin thinking
that way, redemptions become
self-reinforcing.
Imagine you're considering putting fresh
money into a fund. You see that existing
investors have submitted exit requests
equal to 10, 15%, maybe more of the
fund. Do you really want to subscribe
now? Or do you worry your money's going
in just as someone else's money's being
paid out? That's how net inflows
disappear. And once the net inflows
disappear, stage two, the private credit
growth story changes very quickly. And
here's one other point that is
potentially important, though we're
going to we're going to save the
implications for later. Now, Apollo and
its debt solutions fund, the 16.8%
withdrawals, were not entirely from the
U- In fact, very few of them came from
the United States. The most of them, at
least according to the filing, came from
offshore.
US onshore repurchase requests, they
were sequentially around 4.3%, while
offshore redemptions increased sharply
to around 12.5%. And that is worth
noting. It means the redemption pressure
is not evenly distributed. And the
offshore stuff
could be even more concerning because
offshore capital can be more rate
sensitive, more mobile, and more willing
to exit when the confidence turns. And
it also signals institutional,
especially insurance companies, who are
the real ground zero in the story, once
we get past the outside layer that's
wrapped up in these BDCs. These funds
are only the final stage in a complex
arrangement where the money, the real
money, flows through insurance companies
who are promising retirements to their
fund holders. And so, this is not
happening in isolation. According to
reporting from The Wall Street Journal,
Apollo has been in discussions to sell
MidCap Financial Investment Corp, or
MFIC, its publicly listed private credit
fund. So, MFIC is another business
development company, one that makes
loans primarily to mid-sized businesses
through Apollo's mid-cap financial
platform. And loan defaults at MFIC
climbed to 5.3%, and that was in the
first quarter, up from 3.9% back in
December, forcing the fund to post a net
loss of 61 million. So, now we already
have a loss at the same time as lo- loan
default rates are rising. Its shares
have traded around 85 cents on the
dollar relative to net asset value, and
small wonder why. Investors can see
where this is heading and it's not solid
fundamentals. Perhaps most importantly
though, MFIC has largely stopped new
lending. Instead, it's been redirecting
payment proceeds toward share buybacks
and debt reduction. This is potentially
the future for more of the industry.
Remember, this is Apollo II. And it's
exactly what stress looks like in a BDC.
The shares trade below NAV, investors
lose confidence in the marks of the
future returns, the manager buys back
stock because lending into the market no
longer looks attractive, defaults really
rise, growth just completely stops, and
debt reduction becomes the fund's
priority. The point is that one of the
biggest names in private credit right
now is dealing with redemptions in one
vehicle and a reported sale discussions
around another vehicle, both of them
under stress. That's the pattern.
Investors in the one are looking at
what's already happening in the other,
the one that no one at Apollo wants to
talk about, which is almost certainly
why they tried to sell the thing.
Investors aren't waiting for what's
happening there to show up in the big
one.
This is why it's critical to watch and
focus on all of these other market
signals and curves and esoteric
indications that we focus on here at
Eurodollar University because we're
looking for clues that this is not being
contained in just private credit. It
pays to know them whether you're an
investor yourself or portfolio manager.
So, join me for my next live webinar
this coming Sunday, June 28th at 5:30
p.m. Eastern Time where we're going to
break down how to unlock all this secret
market that few people follow and even
fewer people truly understand. How to
fit everything into a disciplined
all-weather investing strategy. All the
deeper looks at this stuff that we don't
get into, we can't get into here on
YouTube. We don't want you to react to
the markets, learn to read what
information they're already trying to
tell you. So again, Sunday, this coming
Sunday, June 28th, 5:30 p.m. Eastern
Time. There's a link in the description
to sign up. It's free to sign up. It's
free to attend. I really hope to see you
there because it will be worth your time
to be there. And of course, these
publicly traded BDCs like MFIC are an
important window into some level of
price discovery because most of these
private credit funds, the shadow banks,
these whatever you want to call them,
not only their assets are liquid, the
funds themselves, the only valuations
you get, the only price discovery you
get is what comes from the funds
themselves. So, at least in the publicly
traded vehicles, the stock market, we
get a sense of what investors feel about
what they're being told, what they're
actually doing, what they're seeing, and
how all of these things really fit
together.
Because these publicly traded BDCs do
have share prices. They report their
NAVs, they disclose defaults, and they
pay dividends, and issue debt. They
either trade at premiums or discounts,
which makes them and their stock prices
incredibly useful. And right now, the
entire sector continues to flash deeper
and deeper warnings. Many of them have
traded at discounts since last fall
because investors are worried about
exactly what we're talking about here,
mounting losses, the downturn in the
credit cycle, and not wanting to be
locked into these things. Moody's, for
example, has revised its outlook for
private credit investment vehicles to
negative, citing redemptions from
non-traded vehicles and elevated
leverage in publicly traded
counterparts. And that is another major
shift. For more than 2 years, Moody's
had kept the outlook stable. Now,
they've shifted to negative. Why? Again,
redemptions are rising, leverage is
already elevated no matter what the
managers themselves continue to say to
reassure you that they don't have much
leverage, and the sector's becoming more
vulnerable to these growing shocks, this
growing shock. This is how stress
migrates. This is one part of the
contagion path.
And this is the transition that really
matters. It starts out with some
stresses we know about, you know, we
talked about stage one, stage two, and
stage three. But how do we get from
stage one to stage two, where we are,
and then stage two to stage three. Well,
we start out with stage one credit
stress, default start to rise, borrowers
struggle, some loans get restructured,
and valuations have to start to be
questioned. But then you start to see
stress on trust. Investors start
wondering whether the marks are real,
they start asking whether the dividend
is sustainable, is it going to get cut?
Then they wonder why so many investors
are trying to get out in the first
place, and that's where we are moving
now. And once the issue becomes trust,
the problem is no longer contained to
just one fund. This is why Apollo's
16.8% redemption request number matters
so much. It's not just a withdrawal
statistic, it is a confidence statistic.
Investors are looking at private credit
in the entire story and saying, "I don't
believe the spin that this is nothing or
just some minor bump in the road for an
industry experiencing annoying yet
modest growth pains." And then you get
to the more serious stuff. The next
layer, that's insurance. Private credit
is not just owned by wealthy individuals
and pension funds. Insurance companies
have been enormous buyers of private
credit and structured credit assets.
They have been some of the most reaching
of reachers for yield, and that matters
because insurance companies are at the
very least rating sensitive
institutions. They don't just care about
yield, they care about capital charges,
regulatory treatment, you know,
asset-liability matching, collateral's a
big thing, and at the end of the line of
all those things, ratings. If private
credit vehicles or BDC debt begin facing
downgrades, the consequences
are going to spread because a downgrade
can raise funding costs and reduce
collateral value. It forces institutions
to have to hold more capital, which they
don't want to do because it takes away
their ability to generate higher
returns. It makes certain assets less
attractive or even unacceptable for
these insurance companies to buy.
Ratings actions can trigger outright
selling, and if enough insurance
companies try to reduce their exposure
at the same time, then a supposedly
private stable asset class can suddenly
discover that it does need market
liquidity after all. This is where
forced sales become possible. Apollo
itself has already shown how connected
these worlds are. Earlier this year, the
firm restructured another vehicle by
moving about 9 billion of commercial
property mortgages from its REIT into
its insurance company subsidiary,
Athene. Now again,
perfectly legal and rational, but it
shows how assets can move around inside
the alternative asset management and
insurance ecosystem. And when stresses
rise, those connections are really going
to matter. Now Apollo CEO Marc Rowan has
also said the firm moved up in credit
quality in its insurance business. They
cut exposure to riskier sectors like
software and stockpiled roughly $40
billion of cash. That's not panic, but
it is already defensive behavior and
coming from the head of a firm that's
getting hit with major liquidity
withdrawals in one huge fund at the same
time as trying to distance himself from
another one that's already exhibiting
the signs for all the nasty consequences
of the cycle downturn that's driving
everything to begin with. Do you see it?
Apollo isn't just a fund manager. It has
both the insurance and the vehicles to
funnel assets to the insurance. As the
funds experience these various problems,
it may just be a matter of time before
they reach the insurance layer. Apollo,
not surprisingly, is already taking
substantially defensive steps. At the
same time, the fund managers tell us
there is nothing to see here. In
finance, it's always about what they do,
not what they say. And what investors
are doing in taking so much money out is
saying the same thing that Apollo is.
We're getting increasingly defensive and
increasingly negative, no matter what is
being said in the mainstream or by these
industry insiders who have nothing but
glowing reassessments. They can see they
deep down in these shadows, it is a
credit cycle downturn that is developing
and they don't want to get stuck inside
of it. One in six in that big fund are
saying, "I'm not going to be that
person." Now, the industry is going to
frame every problem as isolate. They
already have. But, when you keep getting
more and more one-offs and you keep
getting a pack of lone wolves that only
ever increase investor flight or growing
concerns across, you know, BlackRock,
Apollo, KKR, Carlyle, let's see who
else, uh Blue Owl, HSBCs, all the BDCs,
even insurance companies and now ratings
agencies. At some point, it becomes a
pattern and the pattern is clear. The
private credit boom was built during a
period of enormous demand for yield.
Investors wanted the returns when banks
pulled back from some lending markets.
Private lenders stepped in and asset
managers raised huge amounts of capital
to the point that they all saw the money
coming in and stopped thinking about
intermediation and due diligence and
underwriting. And insurance companies
were right there in the middle of
everything. Everyone wanted the same
thing, income without volatility. Reach
for yield and get it without having to
worry. Already a huge red flag. But,
credit cycles don't just disappear
because the Fed is optimistic and more
often than not of inflationary.
Eventually, that weak underwriting does
show up. You know, you get PIK interest
that begins to rise. Defaults do happen.
And when they do, they tend to spread.
Exit markets and private equity, they
start to close down. Valuations get
questioned and ultimately, liquidity
gets tested and that is where we are
right now. And to be clear, contagion
doesn't mean that everyone fails
tomorrow, that we have another Lehman
Brothers moment. That's not what talking
about here. What we're talking about is
broader consequences that erupt from a
breakdown in private credit that then
potentially spreads to other parts of
the debt markets and the functioning of
the debt markets and how it relates to
us especially the real economy.
Contagion means stress travels. It
starts in one corner, moves through the
system through behavior, funding,
ratings is a big one, and then forced
selling. In this case, the path could
kind of look like this. First, the
redemptions rise in the non-traded
private credit funds. And then second,
those funds honor only limited buybacks,
which create redemption backlogs. And
this is already happening in widespread
fashion.
Third though, new investors really begin
to hesitate to subscribe because they
don't want to fund other investors
exits. So, the net flows start to turn
negative. After that, more funds stop
new lending to preserve liquidity, which
means borrowers who depended upon
private credit face tighter financing
conditions. And that leads to rising
defaults and valuations that are
falling, therefore even more BDCs trade
at even deeper discounts to net asset
values. Ratings agencies, they start to
have to step in and downgrade outlooks
or actual ratings on these BDCs, on
private credit vehicles, or the debt
that's issued by them. Insurance
companies and other rating sensitive
holders reduce their exposures, which
leads to a growing volume of sales in a
market which isn't really able to handle
them. Those asset sales pressure prices,
and the lower prices validate investor
fears, and they restart the cycle all
over again. Financial markets get
volatile. The real economy takes a major
hit as these companies which thought
that they could rely on the debt
markets, they have to really cut back
for their own survival. Retirement
investors who bought annuities and other
retirement products find out the numbers
that they were shown won't actually be
what they actually get. And maybe a few
shadow banks, maybe a couple of these
funds do fail, but by then it would all
be academic. Many people think the 2008
crisis began with Lehman Brothers, when
Lehman Brothers was basically the
confirmation of the final stage. So,
yes, Apollo's 16.8% redemption number
for the second quarter is an incredibly
important figure. Because what it says
is that investors are not buying the
reassurances. And you have to ask
yourself why this keeps happening. What
is it that they're afraid of? And why
are they afraid in increasing and
escalating numbers?
They are no longer simply accepting the
private credit industry's message that
everything is fine. They're asking for
liquidity. The private credit boom
promised high yield, low volatility, and
stability. Now the market is beginning
to test every part of the other side of
that promise, the stability. It's
already happening as we just went over
deeper in the shadows. Look at Apollo.
All of Apollo, including its insurance
subsidiaries, investors went out of the
front door while the insurance tightens
up at the back door. Neither door is
buying the spin that everything is grand
and the fundamentals are solid. They're
preparing for when more people find out
they're not. That's the contagion risk.
And Apollo,
it's not the entire story. It's just one
key important chapter in it.
Because Apollo's redemptions may be the
clearest sign yet that the credit cycle
downturn, the bust, the crisis may have
reached a more dangerous phase. Because
the question now is simple. Is that
16.8%
the peak
or just the next step?
As if this one credit cycle downturn
isn't enough, there's a somewhat
parallel one taking place over in China,
which just flashed a key euro dollar
warning that's all in the video link
below. As always, thank you very much
for joining me. Join me June 28th for
our webinar, link in the description to
sign up. Huge thanks to Euro Dollar
University members and subscribers. And
until next time, take care.